Aleksandr Khozhainov

Frontend Developer

Telephone: +38 068 124 24 77 My Portfolio: https://khozhainov-aleksandr.github.io

Telegram: @Aleksandr_Khozhainov LinkedIn: Aleksandr Khozhainov Email: khozhainov.aleksandr@gmail.com GitHub: khozhainov-aleksandr

Skype: Aleksandr Khozhainov CodeWars: Aleksandr Khozhainov

SUMMARY

1+ years of commercial experience.

Worked 6 months as a React + Next.js developer at a Product company + 9 months as a JavaScript developer at a product company.

Previously completed full-time study at Mate Academy for 4 months and 6 months at Hillel School.

2 higher educations. 12 years of work at sea as part of international English-speaking crews, including 4 years of work as a 3rd mate (this is like an assistant captain).

I am now a software developer working with JavaScript, Typescript, React and am open to learning other Vue / Angular / React Native libraries and frameworks.

FRONTEND SKILLS

- React, Redux, Next.js
- Typescript, JavaScript (ES2015 2019)
- HTML5, CSS3, CSS Modules, Sass (SCSS), BEM, Bootstrap. Fetch, REST API, Web sockets.
- Figma, Photoshop.
- Git/Github, VS Code, WebStorm, Chrome Developer Tools (incl. React), NPM, Webpack, Jira, Trello.
- Algorithms: Solved 190+ algorithmic tasks.
- Basic OOP understanding.
- English: Upper-Intermediate (Conversational English)

CAREER

React Developer

August 2022 to January 2023 (6 months)

Worked on a large project on Web 3.0 (I can't tell much about this project under the contract) in a team of 20+ people, used Jira for tasks, the project was written in React, Next.js, CSS-in-JS, Redux and library Material UI also used Git flow and Bitbucket in project.

HTML coder and JS developer

November 2020 to July 2021 (9 months)

I developed the startup's homepage and the main work was based on the user's cabinet.

The user cabinet had to work on any device, desktop, tablet, or phone and be supported by all browsers, including the old Internet Explorer.

The cabinet was dynamic, a lot of blocks were either hidden or shown when clicked, the transition to other sections was carried out with the help of PHP. Used JavaScript and jQuery library.

EXPERIENCE OUT OF IT

Company: Nordic Hamburg

Position: Able Bodied Seaman (AB) and 3rd Mate. Working area: Worldwide

Work in mixed crews, we communicated in English

Company: Marlow Navigation Ukraine

Position: Ordinary Seaman (OS) and Able Bodied Seaman (AB) Working area: Worldwide

Work in mixed crews (English communication as well)

EDUCATION

2011-2017: Odesa National Maritime Academy. Sea navigator | Master.

2005-2010: Odesa National Academy Food Technology. Restaurant and hotel business manager | Bachelor.

ADDITIONAL EDUCATION

Frontend course at Mate academy (Git, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, React, Web)

Hillel: Front-End Pro, Front-End Basic

HTML Academy

Udemy: WEB-developer, Udemy: Learn to Program in JavaScript: Beginner to Pro.

Sololearn: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript Fundamentals course.

CodeWars: Algorithmic tasks

Book: You Don't Know JS - Kyle Simpson

Book: JavaScript: The Definitive Guide - David Flanagan